幕雨字幕组原创翻译
翻译：Brynt&超威闫叔  校对：Brynt&超威闫叔
时间轴：花格子神尼&拜仁小攀  后期：Brynt
水漾青春
没错  你的确是怀孕了
Oh, yes, you are pregnant.
- 就是那个吗  - 没错
- Is that it? - That's it.
我现在需要测量一下胎儿的大小
What I need to do now is just do a measurement.
这会让我们了解更多信息  所以我...
That's to give us some idea.So I just...
机器显示你已经怀孕了十二周零一天
Well, the machine's saying that you're 12 weeks and one day,
跟你自己估算的日子十分吻合
so that ties in pretty nicely with your own dates.
它已经长出了头  手臂还有双腿
There's a head, arms, legs.
那是它的心脏吗
Is that its heart?
没错  是它的心脏在跳
Yeah, that's the heart beating.
你想拍张照下来吗
Would you like a picture?
罗柏  快点
Robert, come on!
罗柏  要是我迟到了会领不到薪水的  我得走了
Robert, if I'm late, I don't get paid, I gotta go.
包带上
Pick it up!
- 早上好  各位  - 早上好  老师
- Morning, everyone. - Good morning, sir.
早上好  在早会之前我要告诉大家一个好消息
Good morning.We're going to start this morning's
assembly with a really fantastic piece of news.
相信你们很多人都已经听说了  上周琳赛・麦克卡莱姆
Last week, as many of you already know, Lindsey McCallum from 10H
去伦敦参加了第十届国际游泳跳水预选赛
went to the National Swimming and Diving Trials in London.
她非常的成功
She was very successful.
她已经成功进入伦敦12年奥运会英国跳水代表队
So successful in fact that she is on track to represent
Great Britain in the 2012 Olympic diving team.
琳赛  请起立
Lindsey, will you stand up, please?
大家跟我一起向她鼓掌致贺
Join me everyone in giving Lindsey a really big round of applause.
做得很好  非常棒
Well done, brilliant.
嘿  老兄  她人怎么样
Hey, mate. What's she like?
- 还不错  - 是吗
- Sound man, she's all right, - Yeah?
- 对  - 她...紧不紧
- Yeah, - Is she, er, tight, yeah?
什么  老兄  你不能那么问
What, mate! You can't say that.
你不能这样讨论我兄弟的女人
You can't talk about my mate's girlfriend like that.
你这个混蛋真幸运
You are one lucky bastard.
这不是幸不幸运的问题  卡尔  老兄
Luck had nothing to do with it, Carl, man.
你听你说的  难不成是你有魅力
You heard yourself, what, talent is it?
- 魅力那是天生的  是我的精力  - 你的什么
- Talent. Natural ability. Stamina. - You what?!
是靠我的成熟  我的蛋还有那方面的经验
Maturity. Bollocks. Experience.
没错  是你的蛋  你那两颗大蛋
Yeah, bollocks. Big bollocks.
她娘的肯定都欲仙欲死了  你们说呢
I knew for a fact...she's fucking gagging for it, what do you reckon?
你收到我短信了吗
Did you get my text?
他收到她的短信了诶
He got her text.
你还好吗
Are you OK?
哦  我好得很呢  谢了  那你呢
Yeah, I'm perfectly fine thanks, yeah. Are you?
我也很好
I'm fine.
好吧
Good.
就这样吧  待会儿再见
Right, see ya later.
- 怎么啦  怎么啦  - 唔~老兄  你把她惹毛了
- What happened there?- Ooh,mate,you pissed her off.
罗柏  你去哪儿
Rob, where are you going?
- 简直不敢相信  - 琳  等等
- I don't believe that. - Linds, man.
- 琳  - 别碰我
- Linds. - Get off me!
琳
Linds.
你他娘的不准再跟那帮狐朋狗友在背后嘲笑我
Don't you ever fucking laugh at me again like that with your mates.
听见了吗
Do you understand?
- 你是在躲我吗  - 不是
- Are you avoiding me? - No.
那你为什么不回我短信
Why didn't you answer my text?
因为我一直很忙
Because I've been busy.
放屁
You liar.
这件事很严肃  罗柏
This is serious, Robert.
这件事跟我们
This. Us.
跟我
Me.
- 我可是怀孕了  - 我知道
- I'm pregnant. - I know.
这不是在过家家
It's not a fucking joke.
这也不是你跟你那帮蠢货兄弟茶余饭后的笑话
It's not something you can laugh about with your idiot mates.
这是...真的
It's...it's real.
这是真的  这是你的种  你得负你该负的责任
It's happening. It's yours. You need to get your head around it.
你不能再像个瘪三一样  也不能再继续躲着我
You need to stop acting like a complete twat and stop avoiding me.
你得负责任
You need to take responsibility.
- 我是在负啊  - 你没有
- I am. - You're not.
我会负责任的
I will.
我没有...我没有跟你要钱
I'm not...I'm not asking you to give me money.
我也没让你给宝宝买衣服什么的
I'm not asking for you to buy me baby clothes or anything,
但是你得鼓足勇气看着我的眼睛
but you need to find the courage to look me in the eyes
告诉我你的想法  你的感受  还有...
and tell me what you're thinking, what you're feeling and what...
你在做什么  你要做什么
what you're doing and what you want to do.
- 你明白吗  罗柏  - 明白
- You understand me, Robert? - Yeah.
- 你真明白吗  - 当然
- Do you understand? - Yeah.
你娘的最好明白了
You fucking better had.
这些门质量真好  对吧
They're quality, these doors, eh?
700磅一块呢
700 quid a pop.
艾利克斯肯定会爱死这个的
Alex is going to love these.
- 罗柏  - 啊
- Robert. - Yeah?
我说“艾利克斯肯定会爱死这个的”
I said Alex is going to love these.
对对对  肯定的
Yeah, yeah, yeah, definitely.
你今天到底怎么回事
What's the matter with you today?
你的魂儿丢了吗
You away with the fairies?
抱歉  老爸
Sorry, mate.
它们有磁性吗   到底是怎么搞来着
Are they magnetic?Yeah,what's the matter with that?
嗯  对了 下楼去把水烧上  还有硅滑脂拿上来一下
Hmmm.Right,go downstairs,put the kettle
on, and bring me up the silicone grease.
这真是做得不错
This is a job well done.
嗯嗯
Hmm.
- 我等不下去了  - 会很好的
- I can't wait to see Alex. - It's going to be great.
我都不敢相信他会完好无损的回来
I can't believe he's coming back for good.
嗯  我跟他我们俩完全不同  对吧
Yeah, we're quite different, me and him, aren't we?
- 什么意思  - 他比我勇敢多了
- How do you mean? - He's a lot braver than I am.
- 更勇敢  - 对  他年轻有为
- Braver? - Yeah, he does stuff.
- 你也有所作为啊  - 就装个管道吗
- You do stuff. - Plumbing.
装管道怎么又突然惹着你了
Well, what's wrong with plumbing all of a sudden?
装管道没什么丢人的  家家都需要装管道  罗柏
Nothing wrong with plumbing. Everyone needs plumbing, Robert.
你肯定很以他为傲
You must be properly proud of him, though.
我为你们俩都感到很骄傲
I'm proud of you and all.
对  但更以他为骄傲
Yeah, but in comparison,
- 比如说...  - 罗柏
- like when... - Robert.
我只是实事求是而已  老爸
Stands to reason, Dad.
你觉得我更想你多一点吗
Do you think I'm more like you?
罗柏  今天你到底吃错什么药了
Robert, what's got into you today?
- 没有  我就是在想事而已  - 那就别想了
- Nothing. I was just thinking. - Well, stop thinking.
想得太多会让你盲目的
Too much thinking makes you blind.
我像你这么大时就不胡思乱想
When I was your age I wasn't thinking.
我有次一下就捉到三只鸟
I was out there banging three birds at a time.
嗯  好吧
Yeah, right.
而且作为一个学徒  你还有很多事要做
Yeah, and doing an apprenticeship and all,
you've got a lot of catching up to do.
琳
Linds,
能借你点时间吗
can I borrow you a sec?
呃...
Erm...
我只是有点吓坏了而已
I'm just a bit scared, Lindsey.
我知道
I know.
好吧
OK.
我知道
I know.
好吗
Yeah?
但我还是得告诉你
I just had to tell you as well.
我待会儿过去找你  好吗
I'll come find you, yeah?
好吧
Cool.
- 他说什么了  - 没什么
- What did he say? - Oh, nowt.
什么  他什么也没说吗
What, he didn't say anything?
- 那他还好吗  - 嗯
- Well, was he all right then? - Mmm.
爸  这是琳赛  琳赛  咱爸  互相认识一下吧
Dad, Lindsey. Lindsey, Dad. Will, sorry.
- 你好  琳赛  - 您好  很高兴认识您
- Hello, Lindsey. - Hello. Nice to meet you.
我刚把水烧上  你要喝杯茶吗
I've put the kettle on, d'ya want a cup?
不用了  我不喝茶的
No, I don't drink tea.
好吧  好吧
Right. Right.
在学校还好吧
How was school?
我以为你出去了呢  爸
I thought you were going out, Dad.
不用了  艾利克斯打电话说火车八点半才到
Nah, Alex called, his train's coming in at 8.30.
- 是吗  这样挺好  - 你从哪儿过来的
- Oh, really, cool. - Where you been?
游泳池那边
Just come from the pool.
- 你游泳吗  - 不是  我跳水
- What, you swim? - No, I do diving.
跳水吗  很不错嘛
Diving? Very impressive.
嗯
Hmm.
我们去楼上没关系吧  爸
We're just going to go upstairs, Dad, that's all right, isn't it?
- 很高兴认识你  - 我也是  琳赛
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you, Lindsey.
嘘嘘嘘
Sssshhh!
天呐
Oh, my God!
你觉得他听到了吗  琳
Do you reckon he heard, Linds?
琳赛
Lindsey!
“我不喝茶的”
"I don't drink tea."
不喝茶又怎么了  爸
What's wrong with not drinking tea, Dad?
没什么
Nothing.
火车来了
Here's the train.
艾利克斯  艾利克斯
Alex! Alex, mate!
我自己能走回去的  爸
I could have walked, Dad.
别傻了  我们才不会让你走路呢
Don't be silly, we're not going to let you walk.
我挺喜欢走路的
I like walking.
- 你还好吗 儿子  - 还好啦
- You all right boy? - All right.
好孩子
Good lad.
- 你还好吗  小柏  - 见到你真开心
- How you doing, Bob? - It's good to see you.
我也很开心  小柏
Good to see you. Bob.
- 你还好吗  - 嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
- 好兄弟  - 爸  不用你拿
- Good man. - Dad, leave them.
- 没关系的  你歇着  - 把包放下  爸  我说真的
- No, you're all right. - Leave them, seriously.
不  我拿就行了  罗柏  帮你哥拿包
No, I'll carry it. Robert, get his bag.
- 放下  快放下  爸  - 不  你走你的就行了
-  Leave it. Leave it, Dad. - No, go on.
我自己放的柱子  可结实了
I put the banister on meself, solid that.
地毯都是新铺的  你的电热煮沸器  其它电器也都在
All new carpet laid. Your immersion heater, your electrics in there.
还有专门给你打造的厨房
And there's your fitted kitchen.
那你们在这上面花了多少时间
How long have you both been working on this, then?
总共加起来就六七个月的样子  对吧 柏仔
About six or seven months all told, wasn't it, Bobby?
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
我必须得说  我讨厌死这个鬼地方了
I have to say, I fucking hate the place.
什么
What?
又小又脏  又跟狗窝一样臭  还不值钱  你说呢
It's a poxy, little, rank, little shit hole, in't it?
就像是用塑料堆出来的一样
It looks like it's made out of plastic.
我都能想象得到你站在这里告诉所有人
I could just imagine you now. Telling everyone round here,
“我儿子要回来了”
"My son's coming back.
“我给他买了套房子  你们知道吗
"I've got him his own flat, don't you know?
“他去过阿富汗  他他娘的是个当兵的  你们知道吗”
"He's been to Afghanistan, don't you know?
He's a fucking soldier, don't you know?"
我很为你骄傲  艾利克斯  我只是想给你这些而已
I'm proud of you, Alex. I just wanted to give you this.
爸  你不知道我待过什么样的地方
Dad, you wouldn't believe the places I've been to.
你也不知道我见过什么样的事
You wouldn't believe the things that I've seen.
我知道  儿子
I know, boy.
不  你不知道  爸  你屁都不知道
No, you don't know, Dad. You know fuck all.
你还是留着自己养老吧
Shove this place up your arse.
- 别放在心上  爸  - 别说了  出去
- I probably wouldn't listen,Dad. - No,get out.
她是个跳水运动员
She's a diver.
你已经说过了
You've told me that already.
但是她就要去参加奥运会了
Nah, but she's going to be in the Olympics and that.
她真的要去参加奥运会吗
Is she really? The Olympics.
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
- 你要带她去流产吗  - 什么
- You going to get an abortion? - What?
你要我借你点钱吗
Do you need me to give you some money?
我可以借给你  我还是有点积蓄的
I can do, mate. I'm loaded.
我们还没决定要怎么做
We haven't really made a decision on what we're going to do.
你想让她流产的  老弟
You want to get an abortion, mate.
她最后还是会同意的  对吗
She's only going to fuck off in the end, in't she?
孩子会毁了她的  小柏
Babies aren't all their cracked up to be, Bobby.
我见过的最后一个婴儿就在我面前
The last baby I saw had its arms and legs blown off right in front of me.
被美国人的迫击炮炸得血肉模糊  肢体横飞
US mortar bomb misfired.
只是婴儿而已  小柏
Just babies, Bobby.
你不会留下它的  对吧
You're not keeping it anyway, are you?
我也不知道  我们都还没做好决定呢
Well, I don't know, that's what I mean, we haven't made a decision.
你知道这会让爸多难堪吗  看看你所处的环境
What sort of a shithawk dad would you make? Look at the state of you.
我们家不能再多添一个人了  小柏
We don't need any more people, Bobby.
人都他娘的不是东西
People are fucking shit.
而你又多搞出一个
You having another?
继续说啊
Yeah, go on then.
琳...
Linds...
你有没有考虑过...
..have you thought much about...
那个...
like...
呃...
erm...
你是想留下孩子还是...
like about whether you want to keep the baby or...
我什么都还没想过
I've not thought about anything else.
没关系的  你不需要害怕
It's all right, you don't have to be scared, you know.
我其实挺喜欢它的
I quite like it.
- 我能告诉你件事儿吗  琳  - 说吧
- Can I tell you something, Linds? - What's that?
我很喜欢这个镇子
I love this town.
我很爱它
I love it.
我不知道还有什么地方我待得比这儿还习惯
I don't think there's anywhere else I'd rather
be right now at this second than here.
我想这就是我 我想在这里有个好的生活才是我想要的
I reckon that's me, I reckon that's all I want
really, just to have a nice life in this town.
嗯
Yeah.
- 你知道吗  琳  - 什么
- D'ya know what, Linds? - What?
我觉得我们应该争取一下孩子的事儿
I think we should just go for it, you know, this baby business.
人人都觉得我们还年轻  很天真  去他大爷的
Everybody says we're too young or too naive, fuck 'em.
我觉得我们俩在一起会过得很好的
I think we'd be great together me and you.
我觉得我们会在一起过的非常好的
I think we'd be great together.
- 我觉得我们会很优秀的  - 非常优秀
- I think we'd be sterling. - Sterling.
- 嗯  - 对啊
- Hmmm. - Yeah.
- 我确实很优秀   - 我也是
- I do. - Me too.
- 我还想跟你说件事  - 是吗
- I want to tell you something else. - Yeah?
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我告诉了艾莉森我这周开始不去训练了
I told Alison I'd stop training at the end of the week.
那这样感觉如何
How do you feel about that?
我觉得这样做才是正确的选择
I think it was the right thing to do.
对啊  鱼与熊掌不能兼得  对吧
Yeah, we can't have it all, can we?
- 还好吗  儿子  - 还行
- All right, boy? - Yes.
- 你今天如何  - 很忙
- How was your day? - Busy.
我明天早上要早点出去
I'm out early in the morning.
- 几点  - 五点半
- What time? - Half five.
今天过得好吗
Good day?
很好
Yeah, man.
这是什么
What's this?
罗柏  这是我想的那样吗
Robert, is this what I think it is?
你做了什么
What have you done?
在我为你做了那么多之后
After all I've done for you.
我想这肯定是她的
I suppose it's hers.
“我不喝茶小姐”  那个狗屁奥运会运动员的
Miss "I don't drink tea"Olympic fucking athlete.
那个“完美个屁小姐”  她现在还没那个资格  你说呢
She not so high and mighty now, is
she, little Miss fucking perfect?
别这样说  爸
Don't, Dad.
罗柏  你到底知不知道你妈走了之后我工作有多难
Robert, have you any idea how hard I've
worked for you since your mother left?
一个人操持着这个家
Kept all this together.
而你就是这样来帮我的
And this is you just shitting on it.
你就他妈的这么来帮我的
Just fucking shitting on it!
你他娘的不要脸的蠢货  滚出老子的视线
You fucking stupid little idiot! Get out of my fucking sight!
我简直不敢相信你会这样对我
I can't believe you've done this to me.
你娘个十足的大蠢货
fucking stupidity!
这地方有点烂  对吧
It's a bit of shit hole, isn't it?
我其实还挺喜欢这儿的
I quite like it.
其实我也是
Me too actually.
罗柏  你知道我们总会聊一聊的
Robert, you know that we'll be there.
这对你跟对琳赛一样重要
I mean, as much for you as Lindsey, you know.
这样会安心一点
That's reassuring to know, you know,
因为我们有太多要面对的事了
cos, yeah, I know, there's a lot to face.
琳赛告诉过我你爸的事儿
Lindsey told us about your dad.
其实还有你妈妈的事儿也告诉我了
And your mum actually.
嗯  没错  我们家一点儿也不完美
Hmmm, yeah, it's not ideal.
你很期待当爸爸对吗
So are you looking forward to being a dad?
太兴奋了  兴奋得不得了
Buzzing, buzzing.
我都迫不及待了
Everything about it, I can't wait.
我记得....
I remember...
当琳赛出生的时候
when Lindsey was born.
我爱死她身上的气味了
I loved the smell of her.
我就不停的闻着她的头
I kept smelling her head.
我还记得把她带回家第一天的时候
Actually, I remember the first day when I got her back home,
我就那么看着她  然后在想“我到底该怎么做啊”
I was just looking at her thinking,
"What on earth am I going to do?"
我真不知道该怎么办  我当时吓坏了
I really didn't know,I was terrified.
我当时都呆若木鸡了
Petrified I was.
我那时候都二十四岁了
And I was 24 then!
我那时差不多都比你们大了十岁
That's, like, nearly ten years older than yous two.
还有好多事要考虑  因为我现在几乎什么都不懂
Nah, there's a lot to think about, cos
there's so much I don't know about yet.
我已经乱了手脚
Yeah, there's no sort of real way of preparing.
你们会挺过去的
You'll be all right.
我喜欢这个颜色
I like the colour.
是吗
Do you?
这叫做尘糖灰
It's called dusted fondant.
尘糖灰  是这么叫的没错吧
Dusted fondant, is that right?
- 你真喜欢吗  - 当然了  老弟
- Do you really like it? - Yeah, I do, mate.
琳赛选的
Lindsey chose it.
她学过这方面的东西  老兄
Course she did, mate.
她品味不错嘛  对吧
She's got taste, ain't she?
你什么时候才见她
When are you going to meet her?
随便什么时候都行  你看你  滴的到处都是
Whenever, mate. Here, it's dripping all over the shop, man.
诀窍在于要涂得均匀  然后再不停地滚压  知道吗
The trick is get as much on the wall as
possible, and then roll, fucking roll, yeah.
- 我就是这样做的  - 你才不是
- I was. - You weren't.
我先去四周看看你住的地段如何
Nah, just came round to see what
the place is like for you anyway.
- 我马上就去了  - 你不用去的  就留在原地待命就好了
- I'm going now.- You don't have to,man,stick about.
我想去喝一杯  跟我一起去如何
I'm going for a pint. Come with me?
哦~  不了  我还是留在这儿吧
Ohhh! Nah, I'm going to stick around.
我还得刷墙呢
I've got to paint.
这地方不错  老弟
Sweet place you got here, mate.
艾利克斯  待会儿庆祝一下这个地方竣工
Alex, cheers for sorting this place out, man.
- 不了  没什么大不了的  - 不行  这对我很重要
- Nah,it's nothing,mate. - No,it's everything,mate.
好吧  那待会儿见吧
All right, I'll see you later, yeah.
- 他没你想的那样高尚  - 啊
- He's not as noble as you think,you know. - Huh?
你哥啊  有时候你搞得他跟基督再临一样
Your brother. Sometimes you act like he's second coming or something.
- 去你妹的  - 这是真的
- Fuck off! - Nah, its true.
自从我遇到你开始  你就一直在说“我哥这样做的”
Ever since I've met you it's always been, "My brother does this.
“我哥又是那样做的  我哥是当兵的”
"My brother does that. My brother's off in't army.
“我哥甚至可以把水变成他娘的红酒”
"My brother can turn water into fucking wine."
卡尔  老兄...
Carl, mate...
你搬到这儿来你老爸怎么看
So what's your dad saying about you getting this place anyway?
这没什么关系  对吧
It doesn't really matter really, does it?
我们想你回果园了  你知道吗
We're missing you down at grove, you know.
是这样吗
Is that right?
是的  我们还有了新的成员
Yeah. We've got some new recruits as well, yeah.
说实话  他们淫荡得跟婊子一样
They are as dirty as fuck, honestly.
我挺为你高兴的  卡尔  真的  老兄
I'm pleased for you, Carl, mate, seriously.
是你错过了机会
It's you that's missing out.
这个鬼颜色太诡异了
This fucking colour's horrible.
我们做到了  琳  我们有了自己的家
We did it, Linds, we've got our own home.
你还好吗
Are you OK?
需要我帮拿点什么吗
Can I get you anything?
我待会儿要吃个三明治
I'll have a sandwich later.
好吧
OK.
你想要枕头吗
You want to get one of them pillows?
- 你说什么  - 枕头啊  特别是靠枕
- You what? - These pillows,especially for backs.
专门为孕妇准备的那种
For pregnant people.
别闹了
Clown.
那你想要个婴儿车吗
Ah, you want one of them buggies, as well.
就像这样的...
You know, they're proper like...
看起来就像外太空来的一样
They look like they're from outer space or summat.
我要给我们俩买一个  我有一百英镑
Nah, I'm going to get us one of them. I've got hundred pound.
哪儿来的
How?
我爸之前给的
My dad.
都放了好久了  可是我之前不知道怎么花
I've had it ages, I just hadn't known what to do with it.
但现在我知道了
Until now.
但婴儿车比一百英镑还要贵一点  琳
They're a bit more expensive than a hundred quid, Linds.
闭嘴啦
Shut up.
- 你想做个足底按摩吗  - 不想
- Do you want a foot massage? - No.
那我帮你放洗澡水如何
How about I run you a bath?
这个不错
Cool.
- 行吗  - 行吧
- Yeah? - OK.
现在就洗吗
Now?
- 嗯  - 好吧
- Yeah. - OK.
你在想什么呢
What are you thinking?
很多事
Lots.
啊  你作弊
Ah, cheating.
你知道我最欣赏你哪点嘛  老兄
You know what I admire about you, mate?
哪点
What's that?
你总是很支持每一个人
The fact that you're so supportive over everyone.
- 什么意思  - 比如说...
- What do you mean? - Like...
我也说不清楚  陪琳赛去做她的事  游泳啊
I don't know, take the stuff with Lindsey, with her and her swimming.
- 是跳水  - 什么
- Diving. - What?
- 是跳水  - 有什么区别吗
- Diving. - What's difference?
不  说真的  你明白我的意思吗  你总是依着她
No, really. D'ya know what I mean? You've always helped her out.
你现在还真是有一个男人的样子了
I mean, you've proper shown how much of a man you can be now.
听起来怎么不对劲儿呢
Sound sour.
特别是她回去之后  就更需要得到支持了  对吧
Yeah, man,especially with her going back into it,
she needs all the support she can get. Eh?
我是说她回去游泳的事儿
I mean with her going back into swimming.
是跳水  谁告诉你的
Diving. Who told you that?
我自己看见的
I've seen it meself.
是吗
Eh?
对  昨天我回体育馆的时候路过泳池看见她在那儿
Yeah,yesterday, I came back from gym and
walked past the pool and I seen her there.
不  她告诉我她回娘家去了
Oh, no, she's sacked it off, that's what she told me.
不  她没有
No, she ain't.
你怎么了
What's up with ya?
在这儿等着我  卡尔
Wait here, Carl.
罗柏  罗柏  你怎么了  老兄
Rob? Rob, what's up with ya, man?
罗柏  别那么混蛋  你到底怎么回事  老兄
Rob, don't be a dick, what's up with ya? Rob.
那个人跳得很好  是吧
That was a good un', wasn't it?
还不赖
Not bad,
但不及琳赛
not as good as Lindsey.
- 你来这儿干嘛  - 我听说你在这儿
- What are you doing here? - I heard you was here.
我以为你去你妈妈家里了呢  琳
I thought you was going to your mum's, Linds.
你就是那样告诉我的
That was what you told me.
我知道
I know.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你来这儿干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
罗柏...
Robert...
又是“罗柏  没事儿”吗  你他娘的到底在这儿干嘛呢
Robert nothing.What the fuck are you doing here?
嘿  够了啊
Hey, that's enough.
我想回来
I want to come back.
我想回来继续跳水
I want to go back to diving.
当然不是现在  我是说等孩子出生之后
I mean,not now.Obviously.But when the baby's born.
当孩子出生的时候吗
When the baby's born?
我准备回来
I'm going to.
我们讨论了
We've talked about it.
- 你们讨论过了吗  真是好啊  - 罗柏
- Have you? Lovely. -  Robert.
-你跟她说了些什么  - 罗柏  别这样
- What have you been talking about? - Robert,please.
我在跟她说要是在九个月之内回来
I've been saying that if she comes back within nine months,
她还有可能恢复部分水平  否则...
there's a possibility she could compete at regional level or...
这样对吗
Is that right?
当然是对的
Yeah, it's absolutely right.
太可怕了
Terrific.
虽然我觉得我不可能再在奥运团队里争夺一席之地
I mean, I don't think I'll be in contention for a
place on the Olympic team, but, you know,
但我想在休息三周之后就回去继续训练
I was thinking I could be back in training after a three-week rest.
三周
Three weeks?
对  宝拉・拉德克利夫也是在两年后才复出的
Yeah, Paula Radcliffe was back in after two
而且我比她当时年轻得多
and I'm miles younger than she was.
那他怎么办  琳
What are you going to do with him, Linds, man?
你就把他放在池子边
You just going to sit him here by the pool,
把才三周大还在襁褓里的孩子跟记分卡和红牛放在一起
three weeks old with a towel, Lucozade and a scorecard?
我想国家游泳队肯定能帮我找到一家好的孤儿院的
I bet British Swimming would find me a dead good creche.
还有  我希望你别再叫它作“他”
I wish you'd stop calling it a he.
哪儿
Where?
哦  今天真是我的幸运日
Oh, my days!
快点  快跑啊
Come on, move!
罗柏
Robert?
啊  琳  这是艾利克斯
Ah, Linds, this is Alex.
你好  很高兴见到你
Hello, love, pleased to meet you.
- 他要在这儿呆几晚上  - 是吗
- He's going to stay for a couple of nights. - Is he?
我可是久闻你的大名呢  琳赛
I've heard lots of things about you, Lindsey.
- 是吗  - 对  听过你好多事儿呢
- Have ya? - Yeah,lots of good things,yeah,yeah.
你是跳水运动员  对吧
You're into diving, aren't ya?
嗯  这真是非常棒  真的
Yeah, that's really good, that is.
好得不得了  简直太赞了
Dead good, I think that's brilliant.
我自己其实对跳水不是很了解
I don't really know much about it myself.
我之前遇到的人但是玩跳水戏法的
All I've ever come across is...muff diving.
- 天呐  她都不笑的吗  - 别这样  老哥
- Oh,my god,does she have a laugh? - Mate,please.
- 她的脸就跟冰块一样  - 跳水戏法
- Her face was like concrete. - Muff diving!
他为什么不待在你爸家
Why isn't he staying at your dad's?
什么
What?
要是他想搬出来的话为什么不搬到你爸那儿去
If he's had to move out, why isn't he staying at your dad's?
这个房子可是他帮我们找到的  你知道吗  琳赛
It was his mate that found us this place, you know, Lindsey.
你就行行好  他就在自己找到房子之前住几晚而已
It's only for a couple of nights until he
gets himself sorted out, for Christ's sake.
- 最好是这样  - 他是我哥  你知道吗
- It had better be. - He's my brother, you know.
四十五分钟了
That's 45 minutes.
- 她去哪儿了  - 先别管了  小柏
- Where is she? - Ah, just leave it now, Bob.
- 不  这都放学四十五分钟了  - 有吃的吗  我饿死了
- No, what could she be doing for 45 minutes?
- Any food? I'm starving.
- 有  在那儿  - 在那边那个碗橱里吗
- Yes, up there. - That cupboard there?
你都住了一周了  而且现在都放学四十五分钟了
It's a week night, man, and this is 45 minutes after school.
好了  我们之前不是讨论过了吗
There we go.That's what I'm talking about.
- 你在干嘛  - 我要做军队汤
- What you doing? - I'm making army stew.
喔喔喔   咖喱羊肉加豆子  老兄
Woah, woah, woah, jalfrezi and beans, man.
对  老弟  咖喱羊肉加豆子
Yes, mate, jalfrezi and beans.
还有芽呢
And sprouts.
对  还有芽  这才是好的军队汤
Yeah, and sprouts and all, it's good Army stew,
咱有一大壶呢
everything you've got all in the same pot.
再说一遍
Come again?
我说我们有一大罐呢
I said everything you've got in the same pot.
我不知道我是否买过这个
I don't know if I'm buying that, mate.
- 没试过之前先别做评价  - 这可不太好
- Don't knock it till you've tried it. - That's not good.
没试过之前先别做评价
Don't knock it till you've tried it.
- 那个真看起来不太好  - 不  很好吃的
- That's not good at all. - Yes, it is.
- 哦  闻起来好脏的样子  这可不妙  - 听着  老弟...
- Oh,that smells dirty,that's wrong. - Listen,mate...
哦  你去哪儿了
Oh, where've you been?
游泳池
At the pool.
什么  你跟艾莉森在一起吗
What, was you with Alison, yeah?
罗柏  我爱做什么就做什么
Robert,I can do what the fuck I like.
- 是吗  - 对
- Can ya? - Yeah.
那好吧
All right then.
继续去呀
Go on then.
抱歉  是我出毛病了还是怎么了
Sorry, was I out of order then or something?
我一点都不滑稽  但这我就听到这么点东西了
I'm not being funny, mate, but that's all I hear.
去他娘的跳水  跳水  跳水  哦~  操你大爷的跳水
Fucking diving. Diving. Diving. Oh, fucking diving.
难道她该待在家吗  是吗
Oh,yeah,cos she should stay at home,shouldn't she?
是的  她该留在家里打扫房间  为你做饭  对吗
Yeah, cook your dinner for you, clean the
pots after an' all, shouldn't she, yeah?
不是的  老哥
No, mate.
我只是不想让她影响到我们的孩子
I just don't think she's that bothered about our baby.
我告诉你  你有麻烦了  老弟
I tell you what, you've got problems, mate.
啊  真他大爷的臭死人了  艾利克斯
Ah, that fucking stinks of shit, Alex.
从这上面可以俯瞰整个沃尔沃斯了  老弟
Might look very Waltons from the outside, mate,
你有尘糖灰的托儿所跟宜家成套的平装餐桌  但我看得出来
with your dusted fondant nursery and your Ikea fucking
flat-pack fucking dinner set,but I can see it,mate.
尽管你有心
You ain't in control,
但却无能为力
and you want to be.
你在说什么呢
What are you on about?
她会为她想要的不惜一切代价
She's going to do whatever the fuck she wants in life
你绝对不可能有办法阻止得了她
and there's absolutely nothing you can do to stop her.
女人就是这样  罗柏  你现在应该明白这点
That's what women do, Robert, you should know that by now.
你得放开她的手
And you need to let her.
但是你能做的到吗
But can you?
我敢说你根本都不清楚你到底在说什么  老哥
I don't even think you know what you're on about now, mate.
好吧  那你爱她吗
All right, do ya love her?
- 你爱吗  - 爱
- Do ya? - Yeah.
那还真是感人哦  老弟  太感人了
That's dead touching that, mate. Really touching.
你什么都不重视  你根本不
You don't take anything seriously, you don't.
你得让她去做她想做的事儿
You need to let her do what she wants to do, yeah.
还有你的孩子  她爱干嘛你就让她干嘛
And your baby. She needs to do whatever she wants to do an all.
- 他是个男孩  - 好吧  他...他需要自己去做决定
- He.- All right,he -he needs to make his own decisions.
你得自己走出来  老弟
You need to sort yourself out, mate.
再说一句  我不久之后就要走了
Anyway, I'll be gone soon,
我在这儿待够了
I've had enough of it around here.
你要去泳池吗
You going to the pool?
你还好吗  小柏
You all right, Rob?
我不知道
I dunno.
你想进来吗
Do you want to come inside?
嗯
Yeah.
琳
Linds.
琳  世界上有很多人...
There are people in the world, Linds, that...
都是旅者
..that are travellers.
他们什么也不图...
They want shit and...
他们就到处旅游  到处看...
they go places and-and see...
看风景
..see stuff.
艾利克斯就是这样
Alex is like that,
我们的妈妈也是
so was our mum.
我猜你也是
And I reckon you are too.
但有些人并不是那样的
But then there's people that just aren't.
但他们不是坏人  琳  我不是个坏人
They're not bad people,Linds.I'm not a bad person.
他们想稍微驻足
They just want to stay still for a bit.
我觉得我就更像那种人一点
I think that's more like me.
我想我们与众不同   琳  我想我们一直在一起
I wanted us to be different, Lindsey.I wanted us to be together all along,
但是...要比现在更好一点
but...for it to be a bit better.
你还好吗  老兄  好吧
Aright,mate? All right.
还以为你被宵禁了呢  你今晚不工作了还是怎么着
Thought you was on curfew. Is it your night off tonight or something?
你丫的闭嘴  拉兹
Fucking shut it, Raz.
老兄...
Mate...
我听说琳赛的事儿了
..I heard about Lindsey.
抱歉  老兄
I'm sorry, man.
- 要喝啤酒吗  - 不了  老兄  不用了
- Want a beer? - Nah, mate, nah.
很高兴能看到你回来  老兄
Good to see you back here, man.
我马上就走  老兄
I ain't sticking about, mate.
注意安全  知道吗
Keep safe, yeah?
- 有需要就打给我  - 再会了  卡尔
- If you need owt,give us a bell. - See you later,Carl.
祝贺你  是个可爱的男孩
Congratulations on him.He's a lovely little boy.
用你手臂环抱住他的脖子就行了
Just put your arm around him to support his neck.
- 放松一点  别抱那么紧  - 天呐
- Just relax, back down. - Oh, my goodness me.
- 你想抱一下他吗  - 当然想
- Do you want to take him? - Yeah.
我该怎么递给他
How do I pass him?
你就伸出手搂住他的头就行
If you just hold your arms out and just really support his head.
哦~  嘘~
Oh, shush.
你在想什么呢
What are you thinking about?
什么
What?
你看起来若有所思的样子
You looked very thoughtful.
我在想他呢
I was thinking about him.
还有你
And you.
在想我们之间的事
About us.
我的事
About me.
还有我所有
All the things I want to do.
想为他做的事
For him.
我想带他去的所有地方
All the places I want to take him.
给我  把他给我抱吧
Here, pass him here.
准备好走了吗  你准备好走了吗
Good to go? Are you good to go?
诶
Eh?
笑一个
Give us a smile.
乖儿子
Good lad.
咱出发了  首领
Come on, then, chief,
走了  小伙伴
come on, then, mate.
走了  小家伙
Come on, then, buddy.
你就要错过了
You're missing it.
快醒醒
Wake up.
好样~~~的
Yessss!
跳进去了
Get in.
好多了  好多了  你感觉到不同了吗
Much better.Much better.Did you feel the difference?
妈妈真棒诶
What a mum.
谢谢观看  更多字幕请关注“幕雨字幕组”新浪微博